<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Machine Learning on Simply Approximate</title>
    <link>http://www.simplyapproximate.com/tags/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Machine Learning on Simply Approximate</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.simplyapproximate.com/tags/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>AMLCville Retrospective</title>
      <link>http://www.simplyapproximate.com/posts/amlcville-retrospective/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.simplyapproximate.com/posts/amlcville-retrospective/</guid>
      <description>On April 12th, 2018, Charlottesville and the Tom Tom Founders Festival played host to the second annual Applied Machine Learning Conference (AMLCville). I had the fortune to attend AMLCville and listen to talks on a wide range of topics and get to see the amazing ways that machine learning is being used out in the world. AMLCville was split into three different tracks with topic sessions on natural language processing, health care, computer vision, and geospatial analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating Harry Potter with Machine Learning</title>
      <link>http://www.simplyapproximate.com/posts/creating-harry-potter-with-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.simplyapproximate.com/posts/creating-harry-potter-with-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>The other week I came across some work being done by Botnik and Botnik Studios to create strange new things with machine learning. The creation that caught my eye was a chapter for an entirely new Harry Potter book made using a predictive text algorithm like you might find attached to a cell phone keyboard. By training the algorithm on the text of Harry Potter they were able to produce new dialogue and narration that seemed like the original Harry Potter, but is completely new and bizarre.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>