<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Random Ramblings on Simply Approximate</title>
    <link>http://www.simplyapproximate.com/categories/random-ramblings/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Random Ramblings on Simply Approximate</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.simplyapproximate.com/categories/random-ramblings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Patreon Reverses Course</title>
      <link>http://www.simplyapproximate.com/posts/patreon-reverses-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.simplyapproximate.com/posts/patreon-reverses-course/</guid>
      <description>A quick update on what is going on over at Patreon after the announcement last week of changes to their subscription methods and service fees. In a surprising reversal of position, Patreon has decided to not roll out their planned changes. This reversal will keep in place the current system while they find a way forward that allows Patreon to fix the problems that prompted the changes in the first place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patreon: Problems with Disaggregation</title>
      <link>http://www.simplyapproximate.com/posts/patreon-problems-with-disaggregation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.simplyapproximate.com/posts/patreon-problems-with-disaggregation/</guid>
      <description>On December 8th, 2017, I noticed that my Twitter feed was blowing up about the new changes coming to Patreon. The big change that has people nervous is this: starting in late December, Patreon patrons will have to start paying for credit card service fees. This is a change over the previous system where all fees were taken out of the amount the creator received directly. While overall a switch to charging the patrons the transaction fees doesn’t seem like a huge change, the deeper change of interest (to me) is the disaggregation of the transaction fees.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>